

LAUREN FERRETT

DIGITAL MARKETING SPECIALIST

542 Winter Street Old Forge, Pa. 18518 // 570-313-2338

// lferrett@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

Digital marketing professional with nearly 15 years of experience. A creative and detail oriented worker with strong writing and design skills. Specialized training in deploying social media content across multiple platforms. Experienced working in both internal and external communications.

SKILL SET

CONTENT MARKETING
PUBLIC RELATIONS
GRAPHIC DESIGN
WEB DESIGN
WRITING/EDITING
SOCIAL MEDIA
DESKTOP PUBLISHING
SEARCH ENGINE OPTIMIZATION
DATA ANALYTICS

TECHNICALLY

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE

Photostop

InDesign

Illustrator

After Effects

Spark Pages/Posts

SOCIAL/DIGITAL MEDIA

Spark AR Studio

Hootsuite

HTML/CSS

Twitter/Insta/Snapchat/TikTok
MICROSOFT OFFICE SUITE

EXPERIENCE

Aug 2019 - Present TEMPLE UNIVERSITY

DIRECTOR OF OLYMPIC SPORTS DIGITAL MEDIA

Oversees the social and digital efforts for @TempleOwls and 16 Olympic Sport accounts. Coordinates with design team to deploy content across multiple platforms. Supervises a team of six content creators, managing content calendars and paid social. Also serves as the primary PR contact for two Division I athletic teams.

Sep 2014 - July 2019 TEMPLE UNIVERSITY

DIRECTOR OF STRATEGIC COMMUNICATIONS

Served as primary public relations and social contact for Division I athletic teams. Responsible for writing press press releases and developing digital and written content for the web and social media accounts. Created messaging strategies and developed individualized voices for each account. Deployed paid social media advertising for revenue sports. Pitched stories to local and national media and coordinated talent and production for national TV games.

May 2007 - Sep 2014 WELLESLEY COLLEGE DIRECTOR OF SPORTS INFORMATION & COMMUNICATIONS

Responsible for the publicity and promotion of Wellesley athletics teams and development. Managed the Wellesley Athletics brand, including a re-branding project and the launching of two new websites. Served as media coordinator for special events. Coordinated development communications strategies, including mass mailings/email marketing. Managed area budget and hired and supervised staff.

Aug 2005 - May 2007 BLOOMSBURG UNIVERSITY OF PA MARKETING AND COMMUNICATIONS ASSISTANT

Designed promotional and marketing materials for 17 NCAA Division I and II sports teams. Developed print and web content. Designed and wrote media information notes for football games.

EDUCATION

Sep 2006 - Jun 2009 M.S. IT

BLOOMSBURG UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA

4.0 GPA - Coursework included Digital Game Design, Instructional Design, Web 2.0 Technologies, Foundations of Visual Design, Authoring, Multimedia Project Management.

Sep 2009 - Jun 2010 B.S. COMMUNICATIONS ITHACA COLLEGE

Magna Cum Laude

Department Professional Excellence Award

ON SOCIAL

INSTAGRAM // @lif.ipg TWITTER // @LaurenFerrett